<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>electronic on tgauweiler</title>
    <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/tags/electronic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in electronic on tgauweiler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tgauweiler.github.io/tags/electronic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AEG Dryer Bearing</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2021-06-06-aegdryerbearing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2021-06-06-aegdryerbearing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction An AEG dryer was doing strange sounds while turning the barrel. During testing the drum got stock and didn&amp;rsquo;t turn anymore.
Repair Opening  Remove the water tank and 3 screws in the front. Remove two screws in the back to remove the top cover. Remove the side panel by removing two screws on the top and 3 in the back.  Removing the motor  Remove the air flow cover in the back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kärcher</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2021-04-10-kaecher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2021-04-10-kaecher/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After the winter our Kärcher wasn&amp;rsquo;t working anymore. Best guess was that not all water was drained and the cold damaged something.
Repair  Opening is straight forward. The motor screws also hold in the oil!  One compression cylinder did some damage on its plastic duct and damaged the seal around it.
Replacing it was straight forward, but it turns out the main problem was the the pressure line after the motor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercedes key repair</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-10-19-mercedeskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-10-19-mercedeskey/</guid>
      <description>Introduction An old mercedes key refused to open the car and the litte led wouldn&amp;rsquo;t blink.
Replacement The first step was to replace the batteries and test again.
This didn&amp;rsquo;t help, so the next step was to remove the PCB board.
The board came out with two loose parts (bad) and a broken plastic spacer (not so bad).
The parts (one button, one signal modulation component?) did fall off.
The bottom of the PCB did look normal, last time the little spule and the IR component broke off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacBook Air power supply</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-06-06-applepower/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-06-06-applepower/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My macbook power supply cable got the typical apple problem and cracked open at the connector.
For a long time I helped myself with some electronic tape, but after my macbook did some strange sounds, depending on how the cable was lying, it was time to replace it.
Replacement Because I only heard negative things about knockoff power supplies, I decided to fix my original one. For this I ordered a fitting replacement cable for ~12€.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kitchen Scale Battery Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-05-26-kitchenscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-05-26-kitchenscale/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The kitchen scale ate batteries up in no time and these button style ones are pretty pricy. Also if the batteries get low, the scale can&amp;rsquo;t measure heavier stuff and just throws an error. So I opened it up and noticed that both batteries are wired in parallel and are providing 3V. This lead me to the plan, to replace both with two 1.5V AA batteries wired in series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miele Dryer Bearing</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-12-02-mieledryerbearing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-12-02-mieledryerbearing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Our Miele Novotronic T654C dryer was only running for some seconds before stopping and showing &amp;ldquo;Clean Airways&amp;rdquo;. Needless to say this didn&amp;rsquo;t help.
Repair  Open the case by removing the screws in the front and in the back. Notice in a test run that the drum is only twitching.   Suspect a broken starting capacitor, replace, didn&amp;rsquo;t fix it.   Remove all the things to get to the motor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB Temperature Sensor</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-07-11-usbtemp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-07-11-usbtemp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To measure the room temperature with a PC an Arduino nano clone with a DS18B20 temperature was used.
Build For building i used a raster PCB, mostly because for 2 components to design and etch a PCB is pretty overkill. The DS18B20 is a one wire sensor and only needed one extra resistor.
Software The idea was to connect the sensor to a PC and use a simple python script to notify me over Slack if the measured temperature gets to high or to low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeroboy</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-05-26-zeroboy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-05-26-zeroboy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The ZeroBoy is an old GameBoy Classic case with a Raspberry Pi Zero W inside There are many special parts for building this kind of project. I bought a board for the buttons, battery, HD display with HDMI cable and glass, audio amplifier, speaker, printed holder for the boards, charging board and various buttons.
Build I used a case of a broken old GameBoy which was already pretty yellowed. Used my Dremel to cut out some plastic to make everything fit inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Relay</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2017-02-03-remoterelay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2017-02-03-remoterelay/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I had the idea to switch a relay over wifi with an app on my smartphone. For this i needed some board with wifi support and at least one GPIO.
So i bought a ESP8266 board in the ESP-01 variant. Mostly because it was so cheap, ~1€. Then i noticed, that programming it, wasn&amp;rsquo;t working as intended, because the chip needs around 250mW 3.3V to get running and the usb to serial converter wasn&amp;rsquo;t providing that much power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>