<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finished on tgauweiler</title>
    <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/tags/finished/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finished on tgauweiler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tgauweiler.github.io/tags/finished/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego Cable Repair</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-04-25-legocablerepair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-04-25-legocablerepair/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I found one of my old Lego Technic cable. The cable isolation aged not so well and basically disintegrated in my hand. With a little help from Google, I found out that &amp;ldquo;Zwillingslitze 2x0,14mm² einfarbig schwarz&amp;rdquo; is an adequate cable replacement. 5 meters cost me, with delivery, around 5€.
Opening &amp;amp; Repair The new cable is a little bit thinner then the original one, but still looks good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD Player repair</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-04-17-cdplayerrepair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-04-17-cdplayerrepair/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The old ROTEL RCD-971 had the problem of not opening the disc tray anymore. Because i could still hear the motor spinning inside, i suspected the belt transmission between motor and disk tray.
Opening &amp;amp; Repair Opening the case was straight forward.
 Remove the screws on the bottom and back of the case Remove the magnetic disk locking plate Eject the disk tray by spinning the black gear manually Remove the faceplate at the front Unscrew the cd player module from the case Gently unplug all cables to it Lift it up and pull it back gently out   Remove the disk tray by ejecting it, remove the stopper at the end and push the two plastic lashes at each side to unlock it   Remove the black cover over the gears by pushing the lash down and sliding the whole thing upwards  The square belt was still in place, but because age became to lose to unlock the magnet disk holder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WasherRepair</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-08-03-washerrepair/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-08-03-washerrepair/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The old miele hydromatic W701 washer was acting up and not spinning its barrel.
Opening &amp;amp; Repair First i had to remove some screws to swing the front part open with a litte force.
Next came the removing of all screws that hold the motor cables in place.
At this part i checked the resitance with my multimeter between the left and right coals. (Measured at the litte open flat pieces left and right) and got infite resistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CatTree</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-01-17-cattree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 20:31:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-01-17-cattree/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After the cat utterly destroyed her old cat tree it was time to build a new better one.
Building I found a suitable branch with a nice forking. First step was to remove all bark, which was very time consuming. After that i sanded the wood down to remove all hard edges and wiped it down with oil. Then i added a piece of wood as stand and we have our standing tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KnifeBlock</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-01-17-knifeblock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-01-17-knifeblock/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After seeing some cool stuff done with epoxy i wanted to do something wood and epoxy. A knife block sounded like a doable idea.
Building I found a damaged piece of wood and decided to close up the damaged parts with epoxy. The bottom part was really broken out, so i had to add some support wood to keep the epoxy inside.
After the epoxy was dry i sanded the piece down until it was smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESP01 programming board</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2017-02-03-espboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2017-02-03-espboard/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I did buy a ESP8266 board in the variant ESP-01. Mostly because it was so cheap. Then i noticed that programming it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working as intended, because the chip needs around 250mW 3.3V to get running and the usb to serial converter isnt providing that much docu. So I build the given circuit on a breadboard to provide enough power.
Design own platine with Eagle But since that was pretty ugly I decided to build my own platine for it with eagle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>