<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finished on tgauweiler</title>
    <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/tags/finished/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finished on tgauweiler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tgauweiler.github.io/tags/finished/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercedes key repair</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-10-19-mercedeskey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-10-19-mercedeskey/</guid>
      <description>Introduction An old mercedes key refused to open the car and the litte led wouldn&amp;rsquo;t blink.
Replacement The first step was to replace the batteries and test again.
This didn&amp;rsquo;t help, so the next step was to remove the PCB board.
The board came out with two loose parts (bad) and a broken plastic spacer (not so bad).
The parts (one button, one signal modulation component?) did fall off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacBook Air power supply</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-06-06-applepower/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-06-06-applepower/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My macbook power supply cable got the typical apple problem and cracked open at the connector.
For a long time I helped myself with some electronic tape, but after my macbook did some strange sounds, depending on how the cable was lying, it was time to replace it.
Replacement Because I only heard negative things about knockoff power supplies, I decided to fix my original one. For this I ordered a fitting replacement cable for ~12€.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacBook Air power supply</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-09-29-sghdownloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-09-29-sghdownloader/</guid>
      <description> Introduction Had to tape in the not big enough SIM card.
Replacement Conclusion </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kitchen Scale Battery Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-05-26-kitchenscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-05-26-kitchenscale/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The kitchen scale ate batteries up in no time and these button style ones are pretty pricy. Also if the batteries get low, the scale can&amp;rsquo;t measure heavier stuff and just throws an error. So I opened it up and noticed that both batteries are wired in parallel and are providing 3V. This lead me to the plan, to replace both with two 1.5V AA batteries wired in series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego Cable Repair</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-04-25-legocablerepair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-04-25-legocablerepair/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I found one of my old Lego Technic cables. The cable isolation aged not so well and basically disintegrated in my hand. With a little help from Google, I found out that &amp;ldquo;Zwillingslitze 2x0,14mm² einfarbig schwarz&amp;rdquo; is an adequate cable replacement. 5 meters cost me, with delivery, around 5€.
Opening &amp;amp; Repair The new cable is a little bit thinner then the original one, but still looks good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD Player Repair</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-04-17-cdplayerrepair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2019-04-17-cdplayerrepair/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The old ROTEL RCD-971 had the problem of not opening the disc tray anymore. Because i could still hear the motor spinning inside, i suspected the belt transmission between motor and disk tray.
Opening &amp;amp; Repair Opening the case was straight forward.
 Remove the screws on the bottom and back of the case Remove the magnetic disk locking plate Eject the disk tray by spinning the black gear manually Remove the faceplate at the front Unscrew the cd player module from the case Gently unplug all cables to it Lift it up and pull it back gently out   Remove the disk tray by ejecting it, remove the stopper at the end and push the two plastic lashes at each side to unlock it   Remove the black cover over the gears by pushing the lash down and sliding the whole thing upwards  The square belt was still in place, but because age became to lose to unlock the magnet disk holder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washing Machine Repair</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-08-03-washerrepair/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-08-03-washerrepair/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The old miele hydromatic W701 washer was acting up and not spinning its barrel.
Opening &amp;amp; Repair First i had to remove some screws to swing the front part open with a litte force.
Next came the removing of all screws that hold the motor cables in place.
At this part i checked the resitance with my multimeter between the left and right coals. (Measured at the litte open flat pieces left and right) and got infite resistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB Temperature Sensor</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-07-11-usbtemp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-07-11-usbtemp/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To measure the room temperature with a PC an Arduino nano clone with a DS18B20 temperature was used.
Build For building i used a raster PCB, mostly because for 2 components to design and etch a PCB is pretty overkill. The DS18B20 is a one wire sensor and only needed one extra resistor.
Software The idea was to connect the sensor to a PC and use a simple python script to notify me over Slack if the measured temperature gets to high or to low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeroboy</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-05-26-zeroboy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-05-26-zeroboy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The ZeroBoy is an old GameBoy Classic case with a Raspberry Pi Zero W inside There are many special parts for building this kind of project. I bought a board for the buttons, battery, HD display with HDMI cable and glass, audio amplifier, speaker, printed holder for the boards, charging board and various buttons.
Build I used a case of a broken old GameBoy which was already pretty yellowed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cat Tree</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-01-17-cattree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 20:31:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-01-17-cattree/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After the cat utterly destroyed her old cat tree it was time to build a new better one.
Building I found a suitable branch with a nice forking. First step was to remove all bark, which was very time consuming. After that i sanded the wood down to remove all hard edges and wiped it down with oil. Then i added a piece of wood as stand and we have our standing tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Knife Block</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-01-17-knifeblock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2018-01-17-knifeblock/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After seeing some cool stuff done with epoxy i wanted to do something wood and epoxy. A knife block sounded like a doable idea.
Building I found a damaged piece of wood and decided to close up the damaged parts with epoxy. The bottom part was really broken out, so i had to add some support wood to keep the epoxy inside.
After the epoxy was dry i sanded the piece down until it was smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Relay</title>
      <link>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2017-02-03-remoterelay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tgauweiler.github.io/posts/2017-02-03-remoterelay/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I had the idea to switch a relay over wifi with an app on my smartphone. For this i needed some board with wifi support and at least one GPIO.
So i bought a ESP8266 board in the ESP-01 variant. Mostly because it was so cheap, ~1€. Then i noticed, that programming it, wasn&amp;rsquo;t working as intended, because the chip needs around 250mW 3.3V to get running and the usb to serial converter wasn&amp;rsquo;t providing that much power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>